Arjun Srinivasan

arjun010@gatech.edu • http://arjun010.github.io/

SUMMARY

I am a member of the Senior Research Staff at Tableau Research in Seattle, WA. My research is at the intersection of Human-Computer Interaction and Information Visualization. Specifically, drawing upon techniques from multimodal (e.g. speech and touch) and mixed-initiative interfaces, I design expressive and intelligent visualization tools for human-data interaction.

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, Georgia, USA

■ Ph.D. in Computer Science

Aug 2016 - Jul 2020

Thesis: "Combining Natural Language and Direct Manipulation for Human-Data Interaction through Visualizations"

Research areas: Human-Computer Interaction, Information Visualization

Advisor: Dr. John Stasko

■ M.S. in Computer Science

Aug 2014 – May 2016

Specialization: Visual Analytics Cumulative GPA: 3.83 / 4.0

R.V. College of Engineering, Bangalore, Karnataka, India

■ B.E. in Information Science

Aug 2009 - Jun 2013

Cumulative GPA: 8.68 / 10.00

EXPERIENCE

Tableau Research, Seattle, Washington, USA

Senior Research Staff

Oct 2020 - Present

Conducting research at the intersection of human-computer interaction and information visualization.

Microsoft Research, Redmond, Washington, USA

Research Intern, Mentor: Dr. Bongshin Lee

May 2019 - Aug 2019

Developed multimodal interfaces for data visualization with the EPIC (Extended Perception, Interaction & Cognition) Research Group.

Adobe Research, Seattle, Washington, USA

Research Intern, Mentor: Dr. Mira Dontcheva

May 2018 - Aug 2018

Explored user interface techniques to enhance discoverability of speech input in multimodal interfaces.

Microsoft Research, Redmond, Washington, USA

Research Intern, Mentor: Dr. Steven Drucker

May 2017 - Aug 2017

Designed and evaluated techniques to facilitate visual comparison in data visualization dashboards.

Salesforce.com, San Francisco, California, USA

Software Engineering Intern, Analytics Cloud

May 2015 - Aug 2015, May 2016 - Aug 2016

Developed a visualization system for real-time monitoring and diagnosis of service queues across data centers in a multi-tenant cloud architecture.

SAP Labs India, Bangalore, Karnataka, India

Associate Developer, SAP HANA Cloud Integration

Jul 2013 – Apr 2014

Worked on R&D of Business Process Integration solutions on the cloud. Focused on developing proof of concept solutions for database refactoring and database migration.

PUBLICATIONS JOURNAL/ CONFERENCE

<u>A. Srinivasan</u>, N. Nyapathy, B. Lee, S.M. Drucker, and J. Stasko. "Collecting and Characterizing Natural Language Utterances for Specifying Data Visualizations." *ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI)*, 2021 (To appear).

- A. Narechania*, <u>A. Srinivasan</u>*, and J. Stasko. "NL4DV: A Toolkit for Generating Analytic Specifications for Data Visualization from Natural Language Queries." *IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics*, 2021. *equal contribution.
- A. Srinivasan, B. Lee, and J. Stasko. "Interweaving Multimodal Interaction with Flexible Unit Visualizations for Data Exploration." *IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics*, 2020.
- <u>A. Srinivasan</u>, B. Lee, N.H. Riche, S.M. Drucker, and K. Hinckley. "InChorus: Designing Consistent Multimodal Interactions for Data Visualization on Tablet Devices." *ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI)*, 2020 [Best Paper Honorable Mention, Top 5%].
- <u>A. Srinivasan</u>, S.M. Drucker, A. Endert, and J. Stasko. "Augmenting Visualizations with Interactive Data Facts to Facilitate Interpretation and Communication." *IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics*, 2019.
- <u>A. Srinivasan</u>, M. Dontcheva, E. Adar, and S. Walker. "Discovering Natural Langauge Commands in Multimodal Interfaces." *ACM Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces (IUI)*, 2019.
- F. Hohman*, <u>A. Srinivasan</u>*, S.M. Drucker. "TeleGam: Combining Visualization and Verbalization for Interpretable Machine Learning." *IEEE Visualization Conference (VIS) Short Papers*, 2019. *equal contribution.
- <u>A. Srinivasan</u> and J. Stasko. "Orko: Facilitating Multimodal Interaction for Visual Exploration and Analysis of Networks." *IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics*, 2018.
- A. Srinivasan, H. Park, A. Endert, and R. Basole. "Graphiti: Interactive Specification of Attribute-based Edges for Network Modeling and Visualization." *IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics*, 2018.
- A. Srinivasan, M. Brehmer, B. Lee and S.M. Drucker. "What's the Difference?: Evaluating Variants of Multi-Series Bar Charts for Visual Comparison Tasks." *ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI)*, 2018.
- <u>A. Srinivasan</u> and J. Stasko, "Natural Language Interfaces for Data Analysis with Visualization: Considering What Has and Could Be Asked", *Proceedings of EuroVis (Short Papers)*, 2017.
- Y.H. Kim, B. Lee, <u>A. Srinivasan</u>, and E.K. Choe. "Data@Hand: Fostering Visual Exploration of Personal Data on Smartphones Leveraging Speech and Touch Interaction." *ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI)*, 2021 (To appear).
- A. Saktheeswaran, <u>A. Srinivasan</u>, J. Stasko. "Touch? Talk? or Touch and Talk? Investigating Multimodal Interaction for Visual Network Exploration and Analysis." *IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics*, 2020.
- M. Agarwal, <u>A. Srinivasan</u>, J. Stasko. "VisWall: Visual Data Exploration Using Direct Combination on Large Touch Displays." *IEEE Visualization Conference (VIS) Short Papers*, 2019.
- B. Lee, <u>A. Srinivasan</u>, J. Stasko, M. Tory, and V. Setlur. "Multimodal Interaction for Data Visualization." *Workshop at the International Conference on Advanced Visual Interfaces (AVI)*, 2018.
- J. Thompson, <u>A. Srinivasan</u>, and J. Stasko. "Tangraphe: Interactive Exploration of Network Visualizations using Single Hand, Multi-touch Gestures." *International Conference on Advanced Visual Interfaces (AVI) Short Papers*, 2018.
- R. Basole, <u>A. Srinivasan</u>, H. Park, and S. Patel. "ecoxight: Discovery, Exploration and Analysis of Business Ecosystems using Interactive Visualization." *ACM Transactions on Management Information Systems (TMIS)*, 2018
- B. Saket, <u>A. Srinivasan</u>, E. Ragan, and A. Endert, "Evaluating Interactive Graphical Encodings for Data Visualization", *IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics*, 2017.

R. Basole, T. Major, and <u>A. Srinivasan</u> "Understanding Alliance Portfolios using Visual Analytics", *ACM Transactions on Management Information Systems*, Vol. 8, No. 2, Article 1, 2017.

WORKSHOPS

<u>A. Srinivasan</u>, B. Lee, and J. Stasko. "Facilitating Spreadsheet Manipulation on Mobile Devices Leveraging Speech", *Data Visualization on Mobile Devices workshop at CHI 2018*, 2018."

SB. Karthik, <u>A. Srinivasan</u>, N. Elmqvist, and J. Stasko. "Affordances of Input Modalities for Visual Data Exploration in Immersive Environments", *IEEE VIS Workshop on Immersive Analytics*, 2017."

R. Basole, T. Major, and <u>A. Srinivasan</u>, "Sequencing the Enterprise Genome: Interactive Visual Analysis of Multi-Dimensional Alliance Activities of Global Enterprises.", *IEEE VIS business*|vis, 2015.

POSTERS

A. Das, <u>A. Srinivasan</u>, and J. Stasko, "CricVis: Interactive Visual Exploration and Analysis of Cricket Matches", *IEEE VIS*, 2017.

A. Srinivasan, and J. Stasko, "NL4DV: Toolkit for Natural Language Driven Data Visualization", *IEEE VIS*, 2016.

TECHNICAL

Programming Languages

SKILLS

Most experienced with: JavaScript, Python, HTML/CSS, Java, SQL

Familiar with: Node.js, R, C#, C++ Dabbled in: C, PHP, Perl, Processing

Libraries/Frameworks

d3.js, numpy, NLTK, scipy, jQuery, Flask, Express

ACHIEVEMENTS / AWARDS

Winner of Georgia Tech's CRIDC Poster Competition.	2020	
Georgia Tech College of Computing "Outstanding Graduate Research Assistant" Award.		
Winner of Salesforce.com's Analytics Innovation Challenge.	2016	
National finalist of Walmart's Collegiate Innovators Challenge.	2014	
SAP Global Peer Recognition award.	2013	
Winner of SAP Osmosis.	2013	
National finalist (1 st runner-up) of SAP BizTech India.		
Winner of Microsoft India's Windows 8 hackathon.		
National finalist of SAP Dashboard Design Challenge India.	2011	

ACADEMIC SERVICE

Organization Committee

AVI Workshop on Multimodal Interaction For Data Visualization

2018

2016-Present

Program Committee

ACM International Conference on Multimodal Interaction 2020
ACM Intelligent User Interfaces Conference (Posters and Demos) 2020
Workshop on Visualization for AI Explainability (VISxAI) at IEEE VIS 2019, 2020
KDD Workshop on Interactive Data Exploration and Analytics (IDEA) 2018

IEEE VIS, ACM CHI, ACM UIST, ACM ISS, EuroVis, MobileHCI, ACM ICMI,

ACM IUI, IEEE TVCG, IEEE CG&A, INTERACT

Awarded Special Recognition for Outstanding Reviews

ISS 2020, EuroVis 2019, MobileHCI 2019

Teaching Assistant

Reviewer

CS7450 Information Visualization Fall 2018
CS8803 Data Visualization: Principles & Applications Spring 2017

STUDENTS	Amit Navachania Dh.D. CS (Currently at Coordia Toch)	F-11 2010 C 2020
STUDENTS	Arpit Narechania, Ph.D., CS (Currently at Georgia Tech)	Fall 2019 – Spring 2020
MENTORED	Shrishti AK, Masters, CS (Currently at Georgia Tech)	Spring 2020
	Rishab Mitra, Undergraduate, CS (Currently at Georgia Tech)	Spring 2020
	Hayeong Song, Ph.D., CS (Currently at Georgia Tech)	Fall 2018 – Fall 2019
	Kuhu Gupta, Masters, CS (Currently at Georgia Tech)	Fall 2018
	Ayshwarya Saktheeswaran, Masters, HCI (Now at MathWorks)	Fall 2017 – Spring 2018
	Ayan Das, Undergraduate + Masters, CS (Now at KPMG)	Spring 2017 – Fall 2018
	Hyemin Hwang, Masters, CS (Now at Amazon)	Fall 2017 – Summer 2018
	George Wang, Undergraduate, CS (Now at Google)	Fall 2017 – Spring 2018
	Mallika Agarwal, Masters, CS (Now at Uber)	Fall 2017
LEADERSHIP/	Board Member, India Club at Georgia Tech	2017
TECHNICAL	Salesforce.com Campus Brand Ambassador	2016-2017
EVANGELISM	Georgia Tech Career Fair Liason	2014
	SAP Student Ambassador (1st student selected globally)	2013-2015
	Member of the Microsoft India App Review Board	2013-2014
	Microsoft Student Partner	2011-2013

2011-2012

Joint Secretary for the Rotaract Club of RVCE